Esther Nwachukwu

Lagos State, Nigeria

+2348132950585- estynwachukwu2016@gmail.com

CUSTOMER SERVICE | PRODUCT MANAGER | VIRTUAL ASSISTANT

QUALIFICATION SUMMARY

A dedicated and resourceful customer service representative with vast experience in product management. With over 3 years in developing, implementing and evaluating product performance which has help to maximize sales revenue. I possess significant knowledge in problem solving tactics towards achieving customer retention and satisfaction.

KEY SKILLS

✓ Upselling ✓ Google Workspace ✓ Hubspot

✓ Clear Communication ✓ Zendesk ✓ Design and Prototyping tools ✓ Product Development ✓ Jira ✓ Agile project development

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Product Manager 2021 - 2022

Hiremote Africa Remote.

Hiremote Africa is an edu tech company located in 20+ Africa countries. They offer remote jobs training skills to youth in both coding and non coding skills.

- Increased sales revenue by 23% through increased brand awareness by collaborating with sales and marketing department
- Led a team of 3 on product roadmap development across different teams
- Spearheaded a major product redesign to ensure high acceptability by the customers and easy usability with different model, increased margin by 12%.
- Proferred solution to student onboarding process within 2 month, thereby improving the customer journey exprience
- Adopted Agile project management methodology to design additional product base on customer feedback and review, which improve revenue by #5M
- Managed a team of 4, delegating work to complete major projects on-time and on-budget.

Product Manager Associate

2020 - 2021

Influx Limited Lagos

Influx limited is a technology service company providing branch automation, project management, brand support, technology service to client and banks in Nigeria.

- Maintained and documented product backlogs for over 21 IT project
- Collaborated with project leads to develop an effective onboarding system for customer which improve the service level agreements.
- Designed Kanban board on trello to assign and manage task, increasing work efficiency
- Managed workflow and set deadline for all project on project management tools
- Generated operational manaual for operating designed product, to ease customer and increase product acceptability

2019 - 2020

Lapdam Limited Remote. South Africa

Lapdam Limited is a South Africa base company that provide fashion and beauty service, interior decoration and real estate services.

- Deployed Hubspot CRM tools to generate ticket, manage customer sales funnel and assigned complaint to different department, improving the SLA by 20%
- Designed a feedback form on google sheet to collect customer level of satisfaction and improve on service delivery mechanism
- Answered over 50+ calls in a day
- Crafted a sales script which is used by 4 team of cold callers to prospect customer and book appointment with the sales team
- Achieved 90% Customer satisfaction rate as against the 65% recorded in previous years, this was achieved by providing technical support across all company products and services

General Virtual Assistant 2018 - 2019

KanuKree Remote, Lagos

Kanukree is an ecommerce company with wide varieties of product from fast consumable good to gadget and other product. The company is located in Lagos

- Designed a multi-channel campaign increasing brand awareness by 15%.
- Provided exceptional customer support to facilitate 50+ sales per day.
- Leveraged cross-selling techniques to raise average items per order by 1.2
- Implemented upsell feature on website leading to a 22% increase in value per order
- Enabled effective operations of the office through timely completion of essential tasks.
- Implemented electronic file management system, decreasing printing costs by 70%.
- Respond to 100+ comments and messages daily across the company's social media platforms.
- Monitored content and engagement trends, tested new strategies and communicated with key stakeholders to foster understanding of strategy and enhance 34% improvements in KPI's

Customer service Intern 2018 – 2018

EnTrust IT Service Lagos, Nigeria

Entrust IT Service is a web development agency located in lagos. The company helps business to design IT product such as website, mobile app, payment gateway and other IT related services

- Built trust in the company brand by attending to aggrieved customer calmly and helpfully
- Generated tickets for customer complaint using Pipedrive tools and assigned each complain to the appropriate staff
- Collaborated with team of 7 to produce new guidelines , policies for dealing with customers, increasing customers retention by 13%
- Developed and implemented new customer reporting and on-boarding paperwork for internal functions, reducing preparation time of standard new client by 75%

CERTIFICATION

•	Fundamentals Of Digital Marketing.	March, 2022
	Google Digital Workshop	2022
•	Product Management Certification	2022

EDUCATION

• Bachelor Of Agric
Micheal Okpara University of Agriculture

December, 2019 Umudike, Abia State